{
	"lessons" : {
		"1": {
			"practice" : {
				"1": {
					"questions" : [
						{
							"number": "1",
							"question": "_ restautante (the restaurant)",
							"answer": "o"
						},
						{
							"number": "2",
							"question": "_ escritório (the office)",
							"answer": "o"
						},
						{
							"number": "3",
							"question": "_ igrega (the church)",
							"answer": "a"
						},
						{
							"number": "4",
							"question": "_ americano (the American man)",
							"answer": "o"
						},
						{
							"number": "5",
							"question": "_ francesa (the French woman)",
							"answer": "a"
						},
						{
							"number": "6",
							"question": "_ enfermeira (the female nurse)",
							"answer": "a"
						},
						{
							"number": "7",
							"question": "_ água (the water)",
							"answer": "a"
						},
						{
							"number": "8",
							"question": "_ café (the coffee)",
							"answer": "o"
						},
						{
							"number": "9",
							"question": "_ açúcar (the sugar)",
							"answer": "o"
						},
						{
							"number": "10",
							"question": "_ praia (the beach)",
							"answer": "a"
						}
					],
					"type": "FIB",
					"instructions": "Give the correct definite article, *o* or *a*."
				},
				"2 - 1": {
					"questions" : [
						{
							"number": "1",
							"question": "os hotéis",
							"answer": "the hotels"
						},
						{
							"number": "2",
							"question": "os carros",
							"answer": "the cars"
						},
						{
							"number": "3",
							"question": "as praias",
							"answer": "the beaches"
						},
						{
							"number": "4",
							"question": "os livros",
							"answer": "the books"
						},
						{
							"number": "5",
							"question": "os escritórios",
							"answer": "the offices"
						}
					],
					"type": "FIBA",
					"instructions": "Translate the following:"
				},
				"2 - 2": {
					"questions" : [
						{
							"number": "6",
							"question": "a ação",
							"answer": "as ações"
						},
						{
							"number": "7",
							"question": "o homem",
							"answer": "os homens"
						},
						{
							"number": "8",
							"question": "o jornal",
							"answer": "os jornais"
						},
						{
							"number": "9",
							"question": "o mês",
							"answer": "os meses"
						},
						{
							"number": "10",
							"question": "o professor",
							"answer": "os professores"
						}
					],
					"type": "FIBA",
					"instructions": "Give the plural forms of each of these nouns:"
				}
			}
		},
		"2": {
			"practice" : {
				"1": {
					"questions" : [
						{
							"number": "Ex.",
							"question": "Eu e Paulo",
							"answer": "nós"
						},
						{
							"number": "1",
							"question": "Pedro",
							"answer": "Ele"
						},
						{
							"number": "2",
							"question": "Mariana",
							"answer": "Ela"
						},
						{
							"number": "3",
							"question": "Mariana e Sofia",
							"answer": "Elas"
						},
						{
							"number": "4",
							"question": "Eu, Mariana, e Pedro",
							"answer": "Nós"
						},
						{
							"number": "5",
							"question": "Pedro e Paulo",
							"answer": "Eles"
						},
						{
							"number": "6",
							"question": "Mariana e Pedro",
							"answer": "Eles"
						},
						{
							"number": "7",
							"question": "Pedro, Mariana, e Sofia",
							"answer": "Eles"
						},
						{
							"number": "8",
							"question": "Você, Mariana, e Paulo",
							"answer": "Vocês"
						}
					],
					"type": "FIBA",
					"instructions": "Replace each phrase with a subject pronoun."
				},
				"2": {
					"questions" : [
						{
							"number": "1",
							"question": "Ele _ brasileiro. (He's Brazilian.)",
							"answer": "é"
						},
						{
							"number": "2",
							"question": "Você _ de Los Angeles. (You're from Los Angeles.)",
							"answer": "é"
						},
						{
							"number": "3",
							"question": "Helena _ professora. (Helena is a teacher.)",
							"answer": "é"
						},
						{
							"number": "4",
							"question": "Eu _ casado. (I'm married.)",
							"answer": "sou"
						},
						{
							"number": "5",
							"question": "A casa _ grande. (The house is big.)",
							"answer": "é"
						},
						{
							"number": "6",
							"question": "Você _ o novo médico. (You're the new doctor.)",
							"answer": "é"
						},
						{
							"number": "7",
							"question": "Tom _ meu amigo. (Tom is my friend.)",
							"answer": "é"
						},
						{
							"number": "8",
							"question": "Ela _ americana. (She's American.)",
							"answer": "é"
						},
						{
							"number": "9",
							"question": "Nós _ aqui. (We're here.)",
							"answer": "somos"
						},
						{
							"number": "10",
							"question": "Elas _ de Nova Iorque. (They're from New York. [f.])",
							"answer": "são"
						}
					],
					"type": "FIB",
					"instructions": "Complete with the correct form of the verb *ser*."
				}
			}
		},
		"3": {
			"practice" : {
				"1": {
					"questions" : [
						{
							"number": "1",
							"question": "Nós _ de Nova Iorque. _ americanos. (We're from New York. We're American.)",
							"answer": "somos~somos"
						},
						{
							"number": "2",
							"question": "Pedro e Mariana _ casados. Eles não _ solteiros. (Pedro and Mariana are married. They're not single.)",
							"answer": "são~são"
						},
						{
							"number": "3",
							"question": "Os dois amigos _ estudantes. (The two friends are students.)",
							"answer": "são"
						},
						{
							"number": "4",
							"question": "Os três estudantes _ da Califórnia? (Are the three friends from California?)",
							"answer": "são"
						},
						{
							"number": "5",
							"question": "As duas professoras _ italianas. (The two teachers are Italian. [f.])",
							"answer": "são"
						}
					],
					"type": "FIB",
					"instructions": "Complete each sentence with the correct form of the verb *ser*."
				},
				"2": {
					"questions" : [
						{
							"number": "1",
							"question": "Pedro é casado? (Is Pedro married?)",
							"answer": "Pedro não é casado",
							"format": "Não, _"
						},
						{
							"number": "2",
							"question": "Os jornais são americanos? (Are the newspapers American?)",
							"answer": "os jornais não são americanos",
							"format": "Não, _"
						},
						{
							"number": "3",
							"question": "Você é de São Paulo? (Are you from São Paulo?)",
							"answer": "eu não de São Paulo",
							"format": "Não, _"
						},
						{
							"number": "4",
							"question": "Vocês são do Paraná? (Are you [pl.] from Paraná?)",
							"answer": "nós não somos do Paraná",
							"format": "Não, _"
						},
						{
							"number": "5",
							"question": "Carolina é de Boston? (Is Carolina from Boston?)",
							"answer": "Carolina não é de Boston",
							"format": "Não, _"
						},
						{
							"number": "6",
							"question": "As crianças são francesas? (Are the children French?)",
							"answer": "as crianças não são francesas",
							"format": "Não, _"
						}
					],
					"type": "FIBA",
					"instructions": "Answer these questions in the negative."
				}
			}
		},
		"4": {
			"practice" : {
				"1": {
					"questions" : [
						{
							"number": "Ex.",
							"question": "Você e de Roma?",
							"answer": "Não, eu não sou de Roma. Eu sou de Milão.",
							"format": "Não, _. _ de Milão."
						},
						{
							"number": "1",
							"question": "O Senhor é de São Paulo?",
							"answer": "eu não sou de São Paulo~Eu sou",
							"format": "Não, _. _ de Miami."
						},
						{
							"number": "2",
							"question": "Você é de Paris?",
							"answer": "eu não sou de Paris~Eu sou",
							"format": "Não, _. _ de Londres."
						},
						{
							"number": "3",
							"question": "Ela é da Califórnia?",
							"answer": "ela não é da Califórnia~Ela é",
							"format": "Não, _. _ da Bahia."
						},
						{
							"number": "4",
							"question": "Dona Claudia é a nova gerente?",
							"answer": "ela não é a nova generente~Ela é a",
							"format": "Não, _. _ nova diretora."
						},
						{
							"number": "5",
							"question": "Eles são espanhóis?",
							"answer": "eles não são espanhóis~Elas são",
							"format": "Não, _. _ alemães."
						}
					],
					"type": "FIBA",
					"instructions": "Answer the questions with a complete sentence following the cues provided."
				},
				"2": {
					"questions" : [
						{
							"number": "1",
							"question": "Felipe: Oi, Mariana. Tudo Bem?",
							"answer": "Bem, e você?",
							"format": "Mariana: _"
						},
						{
							"number": "2",
							"question": "Felipe: Também. Este é o meu amigo Bill.",
							"answer": "Oi, prazer.",
							"format": "Mariana: _"
						},
						{
							"number": "3",
							"question": "Bill: O prazer é meu.",
							"answer": "Você é americano?",
							"format": "Mariana: _"
						},
						{
							"number": "4",
							"question": "Bill: Não, não sou americano.",
							"answer": "De onde você é?",
							"format": "Mariana: _"
						},
						{
							"number": "5",
							"question": "Bill: Sou da Inglaterra, sou inglês.",
							"answer": "Até mais.",
							"format": "Mariana: Preciso ir. _"
						}
					],
					"type": "DTCP",
					"instructions": "Complete the informal dialogue with the given expressions."
				}
			}
		}
	}
}